Samuel George Morton Papers 1819-1850 Mss.B.M843
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 2.25 Linear feet 5 boxes, 486 items.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 28, 1833; 8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Dr. Flourens of Academy of Science of France is interested in one of our Indian skulls. Mentions Lafayette. Freeman Guide 1506.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 29, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Drake, Daniel, 1785-1852
    Cincinnati; A.L.S. 2p. add. (Contains also a letter from Wm. Wood to Dr. Drake, Sept. 28,1833.) Unlocated April 2011.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct., 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning his collecting expedition. Includes descriptions and drawings of shells.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov., 1833; 8" x 13"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. "Rec. Nov.28,1833." Concerning shells, geology. Includes drawing of a shell.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 6, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning shells, fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 28, 1833; 6 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning shells, fossils.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 17, 1834; 7 3/4" x 10"; Barabino, Joseph
    New Orleans, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning Indian skulls, Louisiana. Freeman Guide 424.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 18, 1834; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning geology. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 23, 1834; 7 3/4" x 10"; Barabino, Joseph
    New Orlenas, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Has been sick. Plans to travel to Yukatan. Freeman Guide 2156.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, March 4, 1834; 8" x 10"; Pitcher, Zina, 1797-1872
    Fort Gibson, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning a "young and distinguished brave." Refers to various Native American tribes. Freeman Guide 333.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, March 5, 1834; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S.1p. and add. Is sending specimens and drawings. Asks for anatomical specimens. Freeman Guide 1298.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, April 19, 1834; 7 1/4" x 9"; Holbrook, John Edwards, 1794-1871
    Hamilton, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning reptiles.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 29, 1834; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning missing box with crania, drawings and other articles.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, June 18, 1834; 7 1/2" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning geology. Mentions Dr. Lyell.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, June 27, 1834; 7 1/4" x 9"; Cutting, John H.
    Barbados, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Is sending specimens. Shells.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, June 27, 1834; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 4p. Refers to a recent volume with beautiful plates. Geology.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Aug. 18, 1834; 8" x 9 3/4"; Tait, Charles, 1768-1835
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Fears that box of bones sent to Mr. Conrad is lost. Refers to Mr. Creagh and Mr. Cooper.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 26, 1834; 7 1/2" x 10"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Rensselaer Institute, Troy, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces Alexander Van Rensselaer.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Oct. 20, 1834; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Pitcher, Zina, 1797-1872
    Fort Monroe, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning "case of Monroe." Is enclosing remarks on consumption among natives.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Nov. 22, 1834; 8" x 10"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S.4p. add. Concerning epidemics in the Ohio valley since the 1770s. Refers to Native American bones.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 4, 1834; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, England, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning British fossils. Geology.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 10,12, 1834; 7 1/2" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning fishes. Refers to Mr. Agassiz.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, Jan.6, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851
    Oaha, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning his travels and collecting.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Jan. 1, 1835; 8" x 10"; Pitcher, Zina, 1797-1872
    Old Point Comfort, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning geology of the "Trans-Alleghanian country." Mentions climate and diseases.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Jan. 30, 1835; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 4p. Refers to Marton's book. Geology. Mentions Agassiz's work on fishes.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Feb. 23, 1835; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, A.L.S. 4p. add. Concerning occurences of certain diseases in Ohio.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, March 13, 1835; 8" x 10"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Refers to politics and military developments. Received skull of Mr. Pearce.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, March 20, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Mentions Cranium owned by Marietta College. Will collect crania from ancient mounds. Freeman Guide 1299.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, March 26, 1835; 8 1/4" x 10 1/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Offers minerals and geological specimens to various institutions. Refers to inequality as cause for all evil.
  - Check for $5.69 payable to Dan. O. Roberts, drawn on the Schuylkill bank, April 3, 1835; 5 3/4" x 2 1/2"; Rogers, Thomas
    Philadelphia, Printed D. S. 1p.
  - Check for $12.74 payable to James McHenry drawn on the Schuylkill bank, April 3, 1835; 5 3/4" x 3 3/4"; Rogers, Thomas
    Philadelphia, Printed D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, April 15, 1835; 8" x 9 3/4"; Wheaton, W.
    West Point, A.L.S. 5p. and end. Refers to diseases at various stations. Freeman Guide 2522.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, April 21, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Peacock, New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Thanks for essay on consumption. Has cases of speciemns, including insects from Mr. Peale. Describes route of imminent journey to Pacific.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, May 7, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 7p. and add. Refers to Thomas Say. Concerning shells.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, June 8, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, A.L.S. 4p. add. Concerning crania. Shells. Freeman Guide 1632.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, June 10, 1835; 7 1/2" x 9"; Cutting, John H.
    Barbados, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning shells.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, June 19, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Describes Baltimore. Wants to sell his collection of shells. Freeman Guide 1503.
  - Letter to [Samuel George Morton], June 21, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    Steubenville, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning opening of "indigene cemetery" and collection of bones. Freeman Guide 1307.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, June 23, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning crania. Freeman Guide 1504.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, June 28, 1835; 8" x 10"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning his collection of skulls. Refers to drawings. Freeman Guide 1505.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 3, 1835; 8" x 10"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Is sending his annotations to the history of the skulls in the collection. Answers several of Morton's questions about skulls, certain Indian tribes, etc.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, July 10, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Peacock, Rio de Janeiro, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Is sending material from the Falkland Islands. Descrtibes collecting activities.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 11, 1835; 8" x 10"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning Morton's offer to purchase collection of skulls and drawings.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 21, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning the sale of his collection of skulls and drawings.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, July 21, 1835; 7 3/4" x 10"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding publication about fossil shells. Mentions Dr. Silliman.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 21, 1835; 7 1/2" x 9"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding an essay on shells scheduled to appear in his journal.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 29, 1835; 8" x 10"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning arrangement of fossils and descriptions in journal.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug. 9, 1835; 6" x 8 1/2"; Auber, Pierre Aléxandre
    Havana, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug. 19, 1835; 8" x 10"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S.3p. and add. Concerning crania. Is shipping boxes with specimens. Refers to Bartram's "Travels in Florida." Freeman Guide 1633.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug. 20, 1835; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, England, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Regarding fossils. Geology.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 25, 1835; 8" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 7p. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug., 1835; 8 1/4" x 10 1/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 2p. add. Laments limited interest in science among political rulers. Refers to eduction, library.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, Sept. 20, 1835; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851
    Fort Vancouver, Columbia River, A.L.S. 4p. Regrading his collecting activities, experiences on his trip. Refers to fishes.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, Sept. 20, 1835; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851
    Fort Vancouver, Columbia River, A.L.S. 8p. List and description of birds he is sending. Includes note concerning Chinouk skulls. Freeman Guide 728.
  - Extract from the minutes of the meeting, Oct. 7, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Philadelphia (Pa.). Board of Guardians of the Poor
    A.D.S: Sam. Hazard, sec. 1p. and add. (Copy send to Dr. S.G. Morton) Thanks for his service as physician of the Phila. Almshouse.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Oct. 30, 1835; 8" x 10 1/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 2p. add. Refers to his collection and library. Comments on political and social developments in Venezuela.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l P(sic) [George] Morton, Nov. 7, 1835; 8" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 4p. Refers to Maclure, a "noble benefactor of the Academy." Mentions Mr. Peale, other members. Concerning skulls. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Nov. 18, 1835; 8" x 10"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning a fossil shell. Is sending bones of various animals, also Mingo skulls. Freeman Guide 1634.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Nov. 24, 1835; 8" x 10"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Advises against Academy building houses. Discusses education, scientific institutions, Venezuela. Mentions native American skull. Freeman Guide 2215.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, Nov. 28, 1835; 7 1/2" x 12 1/4"; Holbrook, John Edwards, 1794-1871
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Sends anatomical specimens, including alligator heads.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 30, 1835; 5 1/4" x 8"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Sends plant specimens.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 30, 1835; 8" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning Mexican skulls, difficulty of procuring "legitimate" specimen. Discusses conditions in Mexico. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Extract from the minutes of the meeting A.D.S:, December 1, 1835; 8" x 9 3/4"; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Thos. D. Mutter. Rec. sec. 1p. Resolutions regarding Dr. Morton's "Notice of the Academy of natural sciences of Philadelphia."
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 8, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1811-1862
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Refers to Natural History Society. Concerning collection of birds from China. Has acquired Indian skull.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Dec. 29, 1835; 8" x 10"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, A.L.S. 4p. add. Concerning shipment of anatomical specimens, including Indian skulls. Mentions manuscript. Freeman Guide 1300.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 2, 1836; 8" x 10"; Arrott, Colin (?)
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning a recent stay in Ireland. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 9, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning Maclure. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Jan. 10, 1836; 8" x 10"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Cuernavaca, A.L.S. 2p. add. Concerning scientific societies. Refers to Venezuela, Dr. Vargas. Freeman Guide 2215.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton:, Jan. 16, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 4p. (mutilated). Concerning shells, fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 24, 1836; 8" x 10"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces Mr. Booth. Refers to his brother, his nephew, and Dr. Hildreth. Freeman Guide 1230.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Jan. 31, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Cuernavaca, A.L.S. 2p. add. Concerning manufacture of zinc plates, dissemination of journals. Comments on trade, slavery, social conditions.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, Feb. 5, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Peacock, Batavia Roads, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Sends animal and plant specimens, also shells and minerals. Difficulty of getting "natives" to work for him.
  - Letter to Samuel [George] Morton, Feb. 8, 1836; 7 1/4" x 9 1/4"; Brongniart, Adolphe, 1801-1876
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 9, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning Mexican skull. Comments on Mexican and Texan affairs. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Feb. 14, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Cuernavaca, A.L.S. 2p. add. Concerning library, skulls. Freeman Guide 2215.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, Feb. 15, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S Peacock, Batavia Roads, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces Mr. Goldsborough, purser of his ship.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, Feb. 15, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Peacock, Batavia Roads, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Has obtained four skulls. Commebnts on disease on board his ship.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, March 4, 1836; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Caldwell, Charles, 1772-1853
    Transylvania university, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks for edition of Mackintosh.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, March 13, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851
    Fort Vancouver, Columbia River, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Has been "quacking" for the hospital. Concerning birds, quadrupeds. Indians are gathering specimens. Freeman Guide 2447.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, March 15, 1836; 8" x 10"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 4p. Sending Indian skull, animal specimens. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to [Samuel George Morton], March 15, 1836; 8 1/4" x 10"; Wied, Maximilian, Prinz von, 1782-1867
    Neuwied, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Thanks for publications. Lost his collection. Mentions Mr. Pitcher.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, March 20, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Cuernavaca, A.L.S. 2p. add.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, April 12, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Townsend, John Kirk, 1809-1851
    Fort Vancouver, Columbia River, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Iroquois report of Mastodon. Freeman Guide 1665.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, April 15, 1836; 8" x 10"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Is sending specimens. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, April 24 (?), 1836; 8 1/4" x 10"; Trudeau, James (?)
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning publication. Desciption of a bird.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, April 28, 1836; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Cutting, John H.
    Barbados, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Conchology. Plans to go to England.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 2, 1836; 8" x 10"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Publications. Mentions Dr. Mantell's plan to move to America.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 4, 1836; 7 1/2" x 9"; Fleming, William
    Manchester, A.L.S. 3 p. and add. Is sending shells and fossils. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, May 10, 1836; 5" x 8"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Got lost on the way to Academy. Mentions Maclure and Mantell.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, May 17, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 2p. add.
  - Letter to [Samuel George Morton], June 17, 1836; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mackintosh, J.
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 4P. Sends new edition of his book. Medical topics.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l Geo[rge] Morton, June 21, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Macao, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Sends an essay, also skulls of Chinese pirate and a "Hindoo." Sickness on board his vessel.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, June 28, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 1, 1836; 8" x 9 3/4"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning cacti and other plants. Mentions Academy, and Mr. M. (Maclure?)
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug. 2, 1836; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1811-1862
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Elected member of Academy. Recommends James Dana.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug. 3, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Aug. 12, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 2p. add. Concerning his property holdings, real estate.
  - Letter to M. Burrough, Aug. 13, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, L. 2p. "Extract" (Probably in hand of M. Burrough) Refers to Maclure's property holdings, intended beneficiaries.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 25, 1836; 8" x 10"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning animal fossils, geology, animal bones. Also crania. Mentions Dr. Tappan. Freeman Guide 1301.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 28, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning crania. Mexican skulls. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, Sept. 16, 1836; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Brighton, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Refers to Dr. Hare and Dr. Harlan.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Oct. 1, 1836; 8" x 10"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 2p. add. Concerning "this half barbarous country." Refers to his property, Dr. Harlan, geology.
  - Letter to S[amuel] T(sic) [George] Morton, Oct. 24, 1836; 8" x 10"; Cutting, John H.
    St. Thomas, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Leaving West Indies on account of his wife's poor health.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Nov. 4, 1836; 8" x 10 1/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 17, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces Dr. John Baldwin.
  - Letter to M. Burrough, Nov. 17, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Peacock, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Describes travels in Indian and Pacific oceans. Refers to diseases, collecting of specimens.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 19, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning crania. Refers to Maclure. Describes "state of feeling" among American citizens in Mexico. Freeman Guide 2212.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 19, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning the death of his brother.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 30, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Vera Crus, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks for two books. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, Dec. 3, 1836; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Conrad, T. A.
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning geology. Fossils. Refers to Mr. Mather.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Dec. 6, 1836; 8" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Dec. 7, 1836; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
    Charleston, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (Signature almost worn off). Refers to the birds discovered by Townshend.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Dec. 27, 1836; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 4p. add. Concerning "propagation of useful knowledge." Inequality of knowledge and property as cause of all evil. Refers to his property.
  - Letter to [Samuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 30, 1836; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Bachman, John, 1790-1874
    Charleston, A.L.S. 3p. and add.
    General note
    Not located 1/11/1996
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 7, Feb. 27, 1837(?); 8" x 10"; Prinsep, James, 1799-1840
    Calcutta, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Elected member of the Academy. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Jan. 16, 1837; 9 1/4" x 10 3/4"; Vargas, José María, 1786-1854
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Acknowledges receipt of letter, diploma, books. Refers to skulls.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Jan. 16, 1837; 9" x 10 3/4"; Vargas, José María, 1786-1854
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. Election to membership.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 19, 1837; 8" x 10"; Falconer, Hugh, 1808-1865
    Bot. Garden, Saharanpoor, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning skulls from Northern India. Refers to geological discoveries.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 1, 1837; 7 3/4" x 10"; Jackson, James, 1777-1867
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning crania. Freeman Guide 1511.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 3, 1837; 8" x 10"; Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1811-1862
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. (On same sheet with letter from B. Silliman, Feb. 4, 1837) Concerning skull. Freeman Guide 3200.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Feb. 3, 1837; 8" x 10"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning skulls. Freeman Guide 728a.